<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>PowerAutomate - Tag - Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
        <link>/tags/powerautomate/</link>
        <description>PowerAutomate - Tag - Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/powerautomate/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Custom document link sharing with Sharepoint and Power Automate</title>
    <link>/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/Dynamicexternalsharing.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseYou need to share a file from sharepoint to an external user, in an automated process. No manual &lsquo;create link&rsquo; actions needed on the sharepoint site. You can then email this link to your external client.
Default on Power automate for a sharing link for sharepoint, is to set the Link Scope to either:
Anyone with the link (including anonymous)
People in your organization
This explains how you can use the &lsquo;people with existing access&rsquo; sharing type.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Quick tip! Unmanaged layers - updates not moving through environments (ALM)</title>
    <link>/posts/unmanagedlayers-alm/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 14:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/unmanagedlayers-alm/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I had this issue today and figured I’d write a quick tip for it.
I’ve changed my app, modified flows, everything works fine in Dev, publish customizations, export as managed and move to Test. Verified the client can see the new app version, and asked her to test.
Uh-oh, the flows aren’t reflecting changes. XML MappingsIssue: Changes made in one environment, don’t reflect in another environment in a managed solutionSolution/Fix: Check on your Flows, or anything not reflecting the changes, for the Solution Layers Go to your flow for example, the ellipsis (…) and check the Solution Layers.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
