<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MSWord on Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
    <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/categories/msword/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MSWord on Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 14:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/categories/msword/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Setting restrictive security on a Word Template while leaving sections open (Restrictive editing)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/restrictive-editing-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/restrictive-editing-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;another-word-tip-oh-my&#34;&gt;Another Word tip, oh my…&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explains how to set security on a Word document, restrict the editing, but allow forms to be filled out, and certain sections to be edited. For example, to add in attachments or images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the most frustrating process, but I hope I can explain it clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find you cannot add a continuous break, but it does a page break, check out this article, or redo your document (that’s what I did)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to repeat words in Microsoft Word (XML Mappings)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/repeatwordsinmsword/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/repeatwordsinmsword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I usually only do Power Platform, but Microsoft Word is bound to be in your project needs someday, or combining with Power Automate, so I figured why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever had the request to have certain words repeated, lets say in a header or footer?
It can be anything, a date, name, product title, Business Unit etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be achieved using XML Mapping in Microsoft Word.
To get to the XML mapping, you must first have the Developer Tab activated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
