<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:27:14 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Adding a decimal count to your Power Automate Flow (Float/Increment variable)</title>
    <link>/posts/countinvariablescont/countinvariablescont/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/countinvariablescont/countinvariablescont/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="count.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I&rsquo;ve explained how to count in a variable, but how do you count in a decimal?
I had a usecase, where we wanted to create a version number metadata field. We could of course use an integer, count using increment, and upload to the field, however that only does &lsquo;major&rsquo; counts i.e 1.0 to 2.0 to 3.0 etc.
How do I count in minor, decimals, from 0.1 to 0.2 to 03 or even 0.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>New options for Gen AI and Bing AI Search</title>
    <link>/posts/copilotstudiogenai/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/copilotstudiogenai/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/copilotstudiogenai/studio.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseYou&rsquo;re trying to use Generative AI features in Copilot Studio, however it says it&rsquo;s not supported. How do you fix this?
Enable the settings for your environmentYou need to be a Power Platform admin for this.
Go to the Power Platform admin center
CLick on your environment.
On the lower right corner, enable these 2 settings:
The 2 new options you need to enable as PP admin for your environmentNow you can use GenAI in your Copilot Studio bot!]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to use the PDF Viewer, to view PDF&#39;s in a Model Driven app from an attachment column</title>
    <link>/posts/pdfviewerincanvascomponent/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/pdfviewerincanvascomponent/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/pdfviewerincanvascomponent/pdfviewer.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseMy PDF viewer works in the canvas app, but not when I embed it
Show image 0/0 in MDA
The beginningI had a need, to display a pdf from a Dataverse attachment column in a Model driven app form.
I had looked at many different PCF Components (which are totally awesome, you should really check them out!) However these only work on Notes with attachments. My dataverse table/solution uses a files column.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Calling a Power Automate Cloud flow, from Power Pages forms (!) using Javascript</title>
    <link>/posts/callpowerautomateflowfrompowerpagesform/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 14:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/callpowerautomateflowfrompowerpagesform/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/callpowerautomateflowfrompowerpagesform/powerpagesflow.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Calling a Power Automate flow from a dataverse form, in a Power Page formSounds easy right? Trust me it&rsquo;s not, but I hope this helps. I have had tremendous help from my colleague Laurens Hoogendoorn, who is completely awesome and helps me run with javascript (see what I did there) before learning how to crawl or walk. LOL. Laurens, you are the best!
So, let me start at the beginning.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to use regex in Power Automate Cloud flows</title>
    <link>/posts/regexinpowerautomatecloud/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/regexinpowerautomatecloud/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/regexinpowerautomatecloud/regex.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I had a client scenario, where I needed to grab a 6-digit number from an incoming email subject. It wont always be in the same place, and also possibly not be the only digits. So I couldnt use trim, length or other that I could think off.
Unfortunately, or luckily, depending on how you look at it, my dear friend Cat Schneider introduced me to regex
When you know you know, regex isnt easy.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to use parameters in an embedded Power BI link</title>
    <link>/posts/powerbiembedparameters/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/powerbiembedparameters/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/powerbiembedparameters/powerbitile2.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>My scenario:This is an addition to my earlier blog, and with a few more parameters you can use. Credits go to https://community.fabric.microsoft.com/t5/Service/All-possible-Power-BI-Service-embed-URL-parameters/m-p/3053763 but I did want to share as well.
I&rsquo;m struggeling to fit a canvas app with a powerbi tile that has an embedded report into a teams app (gotta love it) and my report wont fully fit. I&rsquo;m trying to find the magic combo of these parameters.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to embed a Power BI report into a Canvas app, and hide the nav &amp; filter</title>
    <link>/posts/canvasapppowerbi/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/canvasapppowerbi/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/canvasapppowerbi/powerbitile.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Step 1 - Embed a Power BI report into a canvas appI dont know about you, but it took me a while to figure out why I couldnt add my report into a Power BI tile in a canvas app. I knew I did it before, but of course didnt blog about it, so I forgot (lol)
It&rsquo;s actually really easy, and doesnt require you to reupload your pbix, add to tiles or others.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Filter on date column with random years on Sharepoint</title>
    <link>/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/sharepointlogo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseYou have a sharepoint list with birthdays, on a date column, but dont know how to filter on them to show the last few days or upcoming few days if someone has (had) their birthday.
I couldnt figure out how to do this, and then a colleague of mine Remco Bruijstens (thank you!) suggested this method, and after testing it worked. Kudos to him, and I wanted to share with you how to accomplish this.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How do I automatically have a GUID in my field?</title>
    <link>/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/guidlogo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseI am creating a Model driven app, with a Virtual Table connected to SQL. In my SQL DB I have an external primary key field. How do I get an automatic GUID? The PowerFX code GUID() is not supported on the form.
So I tried to do something on the ribbon, set the field,
With({I:Last(Werknems).TransactionID},Notify( I, NotificationType.Information));Patch(Werknems,Defaults(Werknems), //Row,{TransactionID:GUID()}) However, since my field is mandatory, and it tries to save before it runs this (of course) it was saying the field wasnt filled in.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Virtual Tables - ALM variables announcement &amp; Power Pages</title>
    <link>/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/mppc.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>MPPC 2023 - Getting to announce brand new features!As some of you may have noticed during my MPPC session, I&rsquo;ve been honored to work together with 2 absolute rockstars within Microsoft, to fact check my Virtual Table information, and to get amazing new announcements out there!
Pranita Padalwar Senior Product Manager for Power Pages, very generously provided information I could share for Power Pages which is so amazing I cannot wait to show you here!]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
