<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 09:27:14 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Filter on date column with random years on Sharepoint</title>
    <link>/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/sharepointlogo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseYou have a sharepoint list with birthdays, on a date column, but dont know how to filter on them to show the last few days or upcoming few days if someone has (had) their birthday.
I couldnt figure out how to do this, and then a colleague of mine Remco Bruijstens (thank you!) suggested this method, and after testing it worked. Kudos to him, and I wanted to share with you how to accomplish this.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How do I automatically have a GUID in my field?</title>
    <link>/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/guidlogo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseI am creating a Model driven app, with a Virtual Table connected to SQL. In my SQL DB I have an external primary key field. How do I get an automatic GUID? The PowerFX code GUID() is not supported on the form.
So I tried to do something on the ribbon, set the field,
With({I:Last(Werknems).TransactionID},Notify( I, NotificationType.Information));Patch(Werknems,Defaults(Werknems), //Row,{TransactionID:GUID()}) However, since my field is mandatory, and it tries to save before it runs this (of course) it was saying the field wasnt filled in.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Virtual Tables - ALM variables announcement &amp; Power Pages</title>
    <link>/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/mppc.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>MPPC 2023 - Getting to announce brand new features!As some of you may have noticed during my MPPC session, I&rsquo;ve been honored to work together with 2 absolute rockstars within Microsoft, to fact check my Virtual Table information, and to get amazing new announcements out there!
Pranita Padalwar Senior Product Manager for Power Pages, very generously provided information I could share for Power Pages which is so amazing I cannot wait to show you here!]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to get a PowerBI report in an adaptive card (the hard way) - Update!</title>
    <link>/posts/powerbiinadaptivecards/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/powerbiinadaptivecards/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/powerbiinadaptivecards/powerbireport.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseYou want to show a report in Microsoft Teams, or when someone requests a sales overview of 2022, a card appears with that report in it. You can also of course set up Powerbi alerts as a trigger.
Right now, natively, dynamic reports do not work in cards. However, at MPPC they did announce this is possibly coming!
For now though, here is a way to make this possible.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Custom document link sharing with Sharepoint and Power Automate</title>
    <link>/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/Dynamicexternalsharing.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UsecaseYou need to share a file from sharepoint to an external user, in an automated process. No manual &lsquo;create link&rsquo; actions needed on the sharepoint site. You can then email this link to your external client.
Default on Power automate for a sharing link for sharepoint, is to set the Link Scope to either:
Anyone with the link (including anonymous)
People in your organization
This explains how you can use the &lsquo;people with existing access&rsquo; sharing type.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Calling a number in Teams from a Canvas app</title>
    <link>/posts/teamscallingfromcanvasapp/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/teamscallingfromcanvasapp/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/teamscallingfromcanvasapp/callfromcanvas.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>How do I call someone in Teams, from a canvas app?I have a use case, where someone wants to press a button or phone icon, and that teams calls a specific person, how do I do this?
There are a few ways to call someone:
To a defined global, context, or environment variable Specific persons Pre-defined phone number Use the Launch command to launch a website that in turn launches MS Teams]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Sending an email from a Model Driven App on a command bar button</title>
    <link>/posts/commandbarsendemail/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/commandbarsendemail/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/commandbarsendemail/imagecommandbar.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>What is the command bar?The command bar is the ribbon on top of your Powerapp.
How do I edit this? Go into edit mode for your Model Driven App Right click on your table, Edit the Command Bar This opens the Command bar editor What are the 4 areas? Main Form - This is the one I&rsquo;m focusing on right now Main Grid Subgrid View Associated View Reference materialScott Durow created this and it has been adopted by Microsoft ever since.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Setting conditions on the visible property - Canvas App</title>
    <link>/posts/visibleproperty/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 07:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/visibleproperty/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/visibleproperty/powerappslogo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Setting conditions on the visible property - Canvas AppHow can I hide my items/control based on conditions?
You can of course use an IF statement, or Switch, and work from there.
True - shows the item False - hides the item
But how can I do this dynamically?You can use Environment Variables. These can be changed when you move between environments (for ALM purposes) Set an environment variable in your solution, add the desired persons email address(es) and refresh your datasources in the Canvas app.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Connecting to Virtual Tables in PowerBI</title>
    <link>/posts/virtualtablesinpowerbi/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/virtualtablesinpowerbi/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/virtualtablesinpowerbi/Powerbivirtualtables.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Connecting to Virtual Tables in PowerBIWhen I wanted to connect to the virtual table, my first instinct was to use the Dataverse connector since they are virtual tables, on Dataverse. Opening up PowerBI, connecting to Dataverse, there were no virtual tables visible.
Of course, the work around would be to connect to the source directly, but I did want to see if I could make it work.
Virtual tables are only available in PowerBI through the Common Data Service (Legacy) connector.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Dynamic content not displaying my action</title>
    <link>/posts/dynamiccontent/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:27:14 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>
                        <name>Nathalie</name><uri>https://nathalieleenders.com</uri><email>info@nathalieleenders.com</email></author><guid>/posts/dynamiccontent/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/dynamiccontent/power-autoamte-vs-flow.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>I came across this today and wanted to share. I couldnt figure out why my output from the teams adaptive card was not an option to select in my Compose (no body or anything available). 😭</p>
<h3 id="scenario" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#scenario" class="header-mark"></a>Scenario:</h3><p>You have an action in your flow, for example a teams adaptive card, and want to use the output somewhere. Whether thats in a compose, set variable, update row, doesnt matter. What you try and do, it wont show.</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
