<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Automate on Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/power-automate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Automate on Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/power-automate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>How do I mention someone, through the &#39;post a message to Teams&#39; option in Power Automate?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/teamsmentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/teamsmentions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a decimal count to your Power Automate Flow (Float/Increment variable)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/countinvariablescont/countinvariablescont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/countinvariablescont/countinvariablescont/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve explained how to count in a variable, but how do you count in a decimal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a usecase, where we wanted to create a version number metadata field. We could of course use an integer, count using increment, and upload to the field, however that only does &amp;lsquo;major&amp;rsquo; counts i.e 1.0 to 2.0 to 3.0 etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-count-in-minor-decimals-from-01-to-02-to-03-or-even-001-to-002&#34;&gt;How do I count in minor, decimals, from 0.1 to 0.2 to 03 or even 0.01 to 0.02?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, you can follow the same logic, but use a float value instead of integer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling a Power Automate Cloud flow, from Power Pages forms (!) using Javascript</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/callpowerautomateflowfrompowerpagesform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/callpowerautomateflowfrompowerpagesform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;calling-a-power-automate-flow-from-a-dataverse-form-in-a-power-page-form&#34;&gt;Calling a Power Automate flow from a dataverse form, in a Power Page form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds easy right? Trust me it&amp;rsquo;s not, but I hope this helps. I have had tremendous help from my colleague Laurens Hoogendoorn, who is completely awesome and helps me run with javascript (see what I did there) before learning how to crawl or walk. LOL. Laurens, you are the best!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let me start at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use regex in Power Automate Cloud flows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/regexinpowerautomatecloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/regexinpowerautomatecloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a client scenario, where I needed to grab a 6-digit number from an incoming email subject. It wont always be in the same place, and also possibly not be the only digits. So I couldnt use trim, length or other that I could think off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, or luckily, depending on how you look at it, my dear friend Cat Schneider introduced me to regex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;beakerfunny.gif&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;500&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;800&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully someone within my company helped me guide a regex expression I could use, but I do want to share this awesome resource:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic content not displaying my action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dynamiccontent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dynamiccontent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across this today and wanted to share. I couldnt figure out why my output from the teams adaptive card was not an option to select in my Compose (no body or anything available). &amp;#x1f62d;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have an action in your flow, for example a teams adaptive card, and want to use the output somewhere. Whether thats in a compose, set variable, update row, doesnt matter. What you try and do, it wont show.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another quick tip! Removing blank items in a compose</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/removing-blanks-powerautomate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/removing-blanks-powerautomate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a follow-up post for my earlier blog, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/combinemultipledata/&#34;&gt;Combine data from multiple apply to each into a single output file (Variables and compose)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yerawizardcat.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cat Schneider&lt;/a&gt; helped me tremendously on this one, full credit to her! Find her blog here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;pusheenthankyou.gif&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;800&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;1000&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following these steps, results in some empty values also being added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if there is an empty entry, but the item exists and you specify that item it will show up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get submitted values from your Choices/optionset column in Dataverse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/collectvalues-choiceoptionsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/collectvalues-choiceoptionsets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ever-noticed-that-when-you-select-your-columnname-in-the-dynamic-data-it-doesnt-give-you-the-result-and-it-stays-blank&#34;&gt;Ever noticed that when you select your columnname, in the dynamic data, it doesnt give you the result and it stays blank?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to explain how you can get the value for your dropdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a difference between the display name, and the actual name of that value.
Dataverse often uses &lt;code&gt;@OData.Community.Display.V1.FormattedValue&lt;/code&gt; instead of the previous &lt;code&gt;new_value_label&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your Power automate flow, either run the flow and check the body, or add a Compose step after your Get Items/Update Item etc. step for Dataverse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a count to your Power Automate Flow (Integer/Increment variable)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/countinvariables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/countinvariables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting with an intro to variables, I want to explain how you can use a very simple counter to your Power Automate flow.
Let’s say you have an Apply to each, like 5 entries, and after this you email your client with the combined data from those 5 entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On top of your flow, add an Initialize Variable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Type Integer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave Initial value blank (or select a starting count)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your Apply to each, add an Increment Variable (Increment means to add/change the count)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increment the variable you’ve created on top with 1 in the value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the variable after your Apply to each step wherever you want, and it will give you the count.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combine data from multiple apply to each into a single output file (Variables and compose)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/combinemultipledata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/combinemultipledata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a tricky one to figure out, took me a few hours and failed attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have log entries, and my flow is triggered to email them all that were submitted the day prior, at 8am.
Getting the data into the email pulls it into an apply to each (which makes sense, but is not what I want)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there is a way around the apply to each, but I’ll not get into that here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
