<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
    <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Power Platform Tips &amp; Tricks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Blog series - Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there are a lot of HTTP calls that can be done. I&amp;rsquo;ve touched upon a few, hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve gained a bit more insight in how these work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-takeaways&#34;&gt;Some takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do a lot of HTTP calls in a single flow, there might be a cache issue poking around, resulting in double updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use Term Store values to update, it wont show in the version history. (work around is to append them to a multiple line text field, but this results in a double entry in version history)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - Get term store (for content types)?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-gettermstoreitems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-gettermstoreitems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fetching Terms from a Specific Term Set in a Term Store&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to retrieve all terms from a specific term set within a term store in SharePoint. The term store and term set are identified by their unique GUIDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;identify-the-term-store-and-term-set-guids&#34;&gt;Identify the Term Store and Term Set GUIDs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a SharePoint site with managed metadata, and you need to fetch all terms from a specific term set. For example, all labels from the Status metadata column.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Best practises</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;best-practises&#34;&gt;Best practises&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some best practises I found either online or discovered myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-the-appropriate-http-method&#34;&gt;Use the Appropriate HTTP Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use GET for retrieving data, POST for creating new resources, PUT for updating existing resources, and DELETE for removing resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-proper-permissions&#34;&gt;Set Proper Permissions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that you have the necessary permissions for the operations you intend to perform. This includes configuring the appropriate access levels for users and applications. Proper permissions help prevent unauthorized access and maintain data security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Call a flow from a button</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-callflowfrombutton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-callflowfrombutton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;json-formatting-on-a-sharepoint-list&#34;&gt;JSON formatting on a SharePoint list?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the powerful capabilities of JSON list formatting in SharePoint. JSON formatting allows you to customize the appearance of your lists and libraries, making them more user-friendly and visually appealing. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover how to get a flow identifier, add a column, set JSON formatting code, and additional button formatting options such as showing/hiding based on fields and permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-flow-identifier&#34;&gt;Get Flow Identifier&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get the flow identifier for the specific flow you want to use. This identifier is essential for linking your JSON formatting to the flow. You can find the flow identifier in the URL of your flow in Power Automate. Simply navigate to your flow, and copy the identifier from the URL. Or click on Export, Get flow identifier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Fetching Specific List Information</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-getlistbyname/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-getlistbyname/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fetching Specific List Information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to retrieve the ID and Title of a specific SharePoint list whose title matches a given name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the List Title: You have a SharePoint site with multiple lists, and you need to fetch the ID and Title of a list named &amp;rsquo;name&amp;rsquo; or of course add your own name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Construct the HTTP Request: You can filter on the name, by adding a ?$filter=title to your query. This uses oData filtering.
You can filter on other things as well, you can use basic filtering such as lt (less than) le (less than or equal) gt (greater then) ge (greater or equal) eq (equal) or ne(not equal).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, `Startswith, substringof, and date time functions are supported.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Free vs Premium?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-freevspremium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-freevspremium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;short-overview---when-to-need-a-premium-license-and-when-not&#34;&gt;Short overview - when to need a premium license and when not&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When can you get away with Power Automate free, and when do you need premium when working with http calls?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Free&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Premium&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;SharePoint HTTP request&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Triggers&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;For a selected item&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;x&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;For a selected file&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;When an HTTP request is received&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;HTTP request&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Get - Http get library id by GUID?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-getlibraryidbyguid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-getlibraryidbyguid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fetching a Specific List by Library ID&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to retrieve the details of a specific SharePoint list using its unique Library ID stored in a variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identify-the-library-id&#34;&gt;Identify the Library ID&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a SharePoint site with multiple lists, and you need to fetch the details of a list using its unique Library ID. The Library ID is stored in the variable VarLibraryID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;construct-the-http-request&#34;&gt;Construct the HTTP Request&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the SharePoint REST API to get the list details by specifying the Library ID in the URL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Get - Http get version number</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-getversionnumber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-getversionnumber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fetching a Specific Item from a SharePoint List&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a specific item from SharePoint, with all the metadata, that you can then re-use in your flow. In my example we&amp;rsquo;re going with version number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the List and Item: You have a SharePoint site with multiple lists, and you need to fetch the details of a specific item from a list. The list name and item ID are stored in variables &lt;code&gt;VarListname&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;VarItemID&lt;/code&gt; but you can of course use your own naming method.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Permissions</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-permissionsneeded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-permissionsneeded/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;permissions-needed&#34;&gt;Permissions needed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my testing, I had SharePoint administrator access with full control on the lists, so I could do anything. For most of the calls, I recommend getting SharePoint administrator access to avoid any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;known-error&#34;&gt;Known Error:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the API call throws an error indicating that you&amp;rsquo;re not authorized, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean you don’t have the correct permissions. It could mean you&amp;rsquo;re attempting to make an API call to an area of SharePoint that’s not allowed to be called. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;ve made a typo somewhere or aren&amp;rsquo;t using the correct type of call.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Types in SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-typesinsharepoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-typesinsharepoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-the-sharepoint-rest-api-to-update-metadata-fields&#34;&gt;Using the SharePoint REST API to Update Metadata Fields&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working with SharePoint REST API, you might need to update a metadata field that originates from a content type. To do this, you first need to get the type value from your library. This type value is essential for making the correct HTTP call to update the metadata field. I dont fully understand the inner workings of SharePoint, but without this field being accurate your call wont work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Why do I need X-request-digest?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-xrequestdigest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-xrequestdigest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-it-and-why-do-i-need-it&#34;&gt;What is it, and why do I need it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it as a type of token, that allows you, or permits you, to modify files on SharePoint through an HTTP request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use POST as your method, and need to use Merge in your header, you also need to include a request digest value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without it, you&amp;rsquo;re not authorized to do this action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;httpcall.png&#34;
     
     
         width=&#34;619&#34;
     
     
         height=&#34;288&#34;
     
     
     
 &gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it will look like to use it in a call;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint - Working with folders</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-workingwithfolders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-workingwithfolders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;working-with-folders-and-the-sharepoint-api&#34;&gt;Working with folders and the SharePoint API&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working with the SharePoint API, handling folders can sometimes be tricky, especially when dealing with deeply nested structures. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to dynamically grab the file location regardless of how deep it is in the root or folder structure. We&amp;rsquo;ll also cover how to handle common issues like permission errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dynamically-grabbing-the-file-location&#34;&gt;Dynamically Grabbing the File Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To work with folders in the SharePoint API, you need to use the full path. This ensures that you can dynamically grab the file location, no matter how deep it is within the root or folder structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - Post - Breaking Role Inheritance for a Specific Item in a SharePoint List</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-breakinheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-breakinheritance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking Role Inheritance for a Specific Item in a SharePoint List&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;
You want to break the role inheritance for a specific item in a SharePoint list, for example when you need to set your own permissions on a file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify the List and Item:&lt;/strong&gt;
You have a SharePoint site with multiple lists, and you need to break the role inheritance for a specific item in a list. I have the list name and item ID stored in variables &lt;code&gt;VarListname&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;VarItemID&lt;/code&gt; , but you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to use your own names of course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - Post - Copying a File to a New Location in SharePoint?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-copylistitem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-copylistitem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copying a File to a New Location in SharePoint&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to copy a file from one location to another within a SharePoint site. The source file URL and the destination file URL are known or in variables to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;construct-the-http-request&#34;&gt;Construct the HTTP Request&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the SharePoint REST API to copy the file by specifying the source file URL and the destination file URL in the URL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - Post - Fetching a Specific Item from a SharePoint List by Title and Item ID?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-updatelistitem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-updatelistitem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fetching a Specific Item from a SharePoint List by Title and Item ID&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to retrieve the details of a specific item from a SharePoint list based on the list title and item ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This call is very similar to getting the list item information, but instead of using Get, we use Post, to be able to update our item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the body, you can then specify what you want to update.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - Post - HTTP Update list item term store?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-updateitemfromtermstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-updateitemfromtermstore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a metadata column you want to update, but how to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to update the status field, with a new status from that term set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;identify-the-list-and-item&#34;&gt;Identify the List and Item&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like always, I&amp;rsquo;ll use varsitename in the URL, and in the URI Varlistname and VaritemID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;execute-the-http-request&#34;&gt;Execute the HTTP Request&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this request, I&amp;rsquo;m updating the name_status field. I will have to have queried the term store before, to get the filter array for the status field I want to have it updated to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog series - Post - Revoke permissions to a document through the API</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-setpermissionstoread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-setpermissionstoread/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revoke permissions to a document through the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here comes the tricky part. There are 2 kind (that I found) role types on SharePoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roles from the Roletypekind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;None (Role = 0)&lt;/strong&gt;: No permissions assigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest (Role = 1)&lt;/strong&gt;: Limited access, typically read-only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reader (Role = 2)&lt;/strong&gt;: Can view items but not make changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributor (Role = 3)&lt;/strong&gt;: Can add and edit items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WebDesigner (Role = 4)&lt;/strong&gt;: Can design and manage site content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Administrator (Role = 5)&lt;/strong&gt;: Full control over the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role (UserRoleAssignment).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View (Role = 1)&lt;/strong&gt;: Grants read-only access to the document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit (Role = 2)&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows the user to edit the document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owner (Role = 3)&lt;/strong&gt;: Grants full control over the document, including the ability to manage permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;None (Role = 0)&lt;/strong&gt;: Removes any previously assigned permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1---you-need-to-have-broken-inheritance-first-otherwise-this-wont-work&#34;&gt;Step 1 - You need to have broken inheritance first, otherwise this won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-call-1---get-all-the-groups-from-sharepoint&#34;&gt;API call 1 - Get all the groups from SharePoint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Method: Post
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;URI: _api/web/lists/getbytitle(&amp;#39;@{variables(&amp;#39;VarListname&amp;#39;)}&amp;#39;)/items(@{variables(&amp;#39;VarItemID&amp;#39;)})/UpdateDocumentSharingInfo
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-setpermissionstoread/list0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Http call&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to blog series - HTTP calls to SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/series-http-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog post series on HTTP SharePoint calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the different types of HTTP calls you can make to SharePoint, including GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the necessary permissions required for these calls and how to set them up correctly. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the essential components of an HTTP request, such as headers and body, and explain how to structure them for successful communication with SharePoint.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a decimal count to your Power Automate Flow (Float/Increment variable)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/countinvariablescont/countinvariablescont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/countinvariablescont/countinvariablescont/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve explained how to count in a variable, but how do you count in a decimal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a usecase, where we wanted to create a version number metadata field. We could of course use an integer, count using increment, and upload to the field, however that only does &amp;lsquo;major&amp;rsquo; counts i.e 1.0 to 2.0 to 3.0 etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-count-in-minor-decimals-from-01-to-02-to-03-or-even-001-to-002&#34;&gt;How do I count in minor, decimals, from 0.1 to 0.2 to 03 or even 0.01 to 0.02?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, you can follow the same logic, but use a float value instead of integer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New options for Gen AI and Bing AI Search</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/copilotstudiogenai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/copilotstudiogenai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;usecase&#34;&gt;Usecase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re trying to use Generative AI features in Copilot Studio, however it says it&amp;rsquo;s not supported. How do you fix this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enable-the-settings-for-your-environment&#34;&gt;Enable the settings for your environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to be a Power Platform admin for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the Power Platform admin center&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CLick on your environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the lower right corner, enable these 2 settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;genai.png&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;800&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;600&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can use GenAI in your Copilot Studio bot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked before (about a month ago at the time of this post) but it&amp;rsquo;s not been adding to these options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use the PDF Viewer, to view PDF&#39;s in a Model Driven app from an attachment column</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/pdfviewerincanvascomponent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/pdfviewerincanvascomponent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;usecase&#34;&gt;Usecase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PDF viewer works in the canvas app, but not when I embed it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show image 0/0 in MDA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beginning&#34;&gt;The beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a need, to display a pdf from a Dataverse attachment column in a Model driven app form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had looked at many different PCF Components (which are totally awesome, you should really check them out!)
However these only work on Notes with attachments. My dataverse table/solution uses a files column.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling a Power Automate Cloud flow, from Power Pages forms (!) using Javascript</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/callpowerautomateflowfrompowerpagesform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/callpowerautomateflowfrompowerpagesform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;calling-a-power-automate-flow-from-a-dataverse-form-in-a-power-page-form&#34;&gt;Calling a Power Automate flow from a dataverse form, in a Power Page form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds easy right? Trust me it&amp;rsquo;s not, but I hope this helps. I have had tremendous help from my colleague Laurens Hoogendoorn, who is completely awesome and helps me run with javascript (see what I did there) before learning how to crawl or walk. LOL. Laurens, you are the best!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let me start at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use regex in Power Automate Cloud flows</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/regexinpowerautomatecloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/regexinpowerautomatecloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a client scenario, where I needed to grab a 6-digit number from an incoming email subject. It wont always be in the same place, and also possibly not be the only digits. So I couldnt use trim, length or other that I could think off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, or luckily, depending on how you look at it, my dear friend Cat Schneider introduced me to regex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;beakerfunny.gif&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;500&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;800&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully someone within my company helped me guide a regex expression I could use, but I do want to share this awesome resource:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use parameters in an embedded Power BI link</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/powerbiembedparameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/powerbiembedparameters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-scenario&#34;&gt;My scenario:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an addition to my earlier blog, and with a few more parameters you can use. Credits go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.fabric.microsoft.com/t5/Service/All-possible-Power-BI-Service-embed-URL-parameters/m-p/3053763&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://community.fabric.microsoft.com/t5/Service/All-possible-Power-BI-Service-embed-URL-parameters/m-p/3053763&lt;/a&gt; but I did want to share as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m struggeling to fit a canvas app with a powerbi tile that has an embedded report into a teams app (gotta love it) and my report wont fully fit. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find the magic combo of these parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-use-these-parameters&#34;&gt;How do I use these parameters?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the embedded URL from your report (Go to export, and copy the embed link)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to embed a Power BI report into a Canvas app, and hide the nav &amp; filter</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/canvasapppowerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/canvasapppowerbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1---embed-a-power-bi-report-into-a-canvas-app&#34;&gt;Step 1 - Embed a Power BI report into a canvas app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dont know about you, but it took me a while to figure out why I couldnt add my report into a Power BI tile in a canvas app.
I knew I did it before, but of course didnt blog about it, so I forgot (lol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually really easy, and doesnt require you to reupload your pbix, add to tiles or others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filter on date column with random years on SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/sharepointfilteronyear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;usecase&#34;&gt;Usecase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a SharePoint list with birthdays, on a date column, but dont know how to filter on them to show the last few days or upcoming few days if someone has (had) their birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldnt figure out how to do this, and then a colleague of mine Remco Bruijstens (thank you!) suggested this method, and after testing it worked.
Kudos to him, and I wanted to share with you how to accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I automatically have a GUID in my field?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/guidjavascriptinmodeldrivenapps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;usecase&#34;&gt;Usecase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am creating a Model driven app, with a Virtual Table connected to SQL. In my SQL DB I have an external primary key field. How do I get an automatic GUID? The PowerFX code GUID() is not supported on the form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I tried to do something on the ribbon, set the field,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerFX&#34; data-lang=&#34;PowerFX&#34;&gt;With({I:Last(Werknems).TransactionID},Notify( I, NotificationType.Information));
    Patch(
        Werknems,
       Defaults(Werknems), //Row,
        {TransactionID:GUID()
        }
    )
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, since my field is mandatory, and it tries to save before it runs this (of course) it was saying the field wasnt filled in. So this didnt work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Tables - ALM variables announcement &amp; Power Pages</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/virtualtablesmppc23announcements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mppc-2023---getting-to-announce-brand-new-features&#34;&gt;MPPC 2023 - Getting to announce brand new features!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some of you may have noticed during my MPPC session, I&amp;rsquo;ve been honored to work together with 2 absolute rockstars within Microsoft, to fact check my Virtual Table information, and to get amazing new announcements out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranita225/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pranita Padalwar&lt;/a&gt; Senior Product Manager for Power Pages, very generously provided information I could share for Power Pages which is so amazing I cannot wait to show you here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get a PowerBI report in an adaptive card (the hard way) - Update!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/powerbiinadaptivecards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/powerbiinadaptivecards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;usecase&#34;&gt;Usecase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to show a report in Microsoft Teams, or when someone requests a sales overview of 2022, a card appears with that report in it. You can also of course set up Powerbi alerts as a trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, natively, dynamic reports do not work in cards. However, at MPPC they did announce this is possibly coming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now though, here is a way to make this possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom document link sharing with SharePoint and Power Automate</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/sharepointlibrarypermissions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;usecase&#34;&gt;Usecase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to share a file from SharePoint to an external user, in an automated process. No manual &amp;lsquo;create link&amp;rsquo; actions needed on the SharePoint site. You can then email this link to your external client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Default on Power automate for a sharing link for SharePoint, is to set the Link Scope to either:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone with the link (including anonymous)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People in your organization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explains how you can use the &amp;lsquo;people with existing access&amp;rsquo; sharing type.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling a number in Teams from a Canvas app</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/teamscallingfromcanvasapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/teamscallingfromcanvasapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-call-someone-in-teams-from-a-canvas-app&#34;&gt;How do I call someone in Teams, from a canvas app?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a use case, where someone wants to press a button or phone icon, and that teams calls a specific person, how do I do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways to call someone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To a defined global, context, or environment variable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre-defined phone number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the Launch command to launch a website that in turn launches MS Teams&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending an email from a Model Driven App on a command bar button</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/commandbarsendemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/commandbarsendemail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-command-bar&#34;&gt;What is the command bar?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command bar is the ribbon on top of your Powerapp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-i-edit-this&#34;&gt;How do I edit this?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go into edit mode for your Model Driven App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right click on your table, Edit the Command Bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This opens the Command bar editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-the-4-areas&#34;&gt;What are the 4 areas?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main Form - This is the one I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on right now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main Grid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subgrid View&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associated View&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reference-material&#34;&gt;Reference material&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Durow created this and it has been adopted by Microsoft ever since. If you need any information on all of the functionality, he has awesome video&amp;rsquo;s and sessions on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting conditions on the visible property - Canvas App</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/visibleproperty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 07:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/visibleproperty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-conditions-on-the-visible-property---canvas-app&#34;&gt;Setting conditions on the visible property - Canvas App&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I hide my items/control based on conditions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can of course use an IF statement, or Switch, and work from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True - shows the item
False - hides the item&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;but-how-can-i-do-this-dynamically&#34;&gt;But how can I do this dynamically?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use Environment Variables. These can be changed when you move between environments (for ALM purposes)
Set an environment variable in your solution, add the desired persons email address(es) and refresh your datasources in the Canvas app.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to Virtual Tables in PowerBI</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/virtualtablesinpowerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/virtualtablesinpowerbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;connecting-to-virtual-tables-in-powerbi&#34;&gt;Connecting to Virtual Tables in PowerBI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I wanted to connect to the virtual table, my first instinct was to use the Dataverse connector since they are virtual tables, on Dataverse.
Opening up PowerBI, connecting to Dataverse, there were no virtual tables visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the work around would be to connect to the source directly, but I did want to see if I could make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-tables-are-only-available-in-powerbi-through-the-common-data-service-legacy-connector&#34;&gt;Virtual tables are only available in PowerBI through the Common Data Service (Legacy) connector.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This connector is available for:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic content not displaying my action</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/dynamiccontent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/dynamiccontent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across this today and wanted to share. I couldnt figure out why my output from the teams adaptive card was not an option to select in my Compose (no body or anything available). &amp;#x1f62d;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario&#34;&gt;Scenario:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have an action in your flow, for example a teams adaptive card, and want to use the output somewhere. Whether thats in a compose, set variable, update row, doesnt matter. What you try and do, it wont show.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributed to the Microsoft New Speaker Community Day 2023</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/speakercommunityday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 11:27:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/speakercommunityday/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve submitted 2 videos to aid new community speakers/bloggers on imposter syndrome, and blogging/speaking</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secret to doing Microsoft exams for free!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/microsoftexams-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/microsoftexams-secrets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip! Using QuickChart.IO with dynamic values (Canvas app edition)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/quickchartiodynamic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/quickchartiodynamic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(This is lengthy for a quick tip, whoops, scroll all the way down to quickly check the fix)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, FULL credit goes to Pen Warner who graciously shared his QuickchartIO code with me that he used for his app. His app is awesome, check that out here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’s on Twitter here: @p3nf0ld
His Blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was trying to do dynamic data into a quickchart.IO code, which I learned how to do in Kristine’s video here
Go check her out as well, she’s awesome!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting restrictive security on a Word Template while leaving sections open (Restrictive editing)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/restrictive-editing-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/restrictive-editing-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;another-word-tip-oh-my&#34;&gt;Another Word tip, oh my…&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This explains how to set security on a Word document, restrict the editing, but allow forms to be filled out, and certain sections to be edited. For example, to add in attachments or images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the most frustrating process, but I hope I can explain it clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find you cannot add a continuous break, but it does a page break, check out this article, or redo your document (that’s what I did)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Process Flow - How to automate moving through different stages</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/bpf-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/bpf-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-move-stages-automatically-bpf-using-power-automate-no-http-calls-needed&#34;&gt;How to move stages automatically (BPF) using Power Automate (no http calls needed)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick summary: You need to grab data from 3 different tables, link them using lookup columns, capture ID&amp;rsquo;s, and add in conditions and use Data operations to shape the data into usable steps. Then add in a switch depending on your stage names, and add final actions updating your BPF table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds easy enough right?…..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;download.gif&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;150&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;400&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps, and I tried explaining it clearly, please let me know in case of any questions, feedback, other methods etc. For me this worked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to repeat words in Microsoft Word (XML Mappings)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/repeatwordsinmsword/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/repeatwordsinmsword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I usually only do Power Platform, but Microsoft Word is bound to be in your project needs someday, or combining with Power Automate, so I figured why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever had the request to have certain words repeated, lets say in a header or footer?
It can be anything, a date, name, product title, Business Unit etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be achieved using XML Mapping in Microsoft Word.
To get to the XML mapping, you must first have the Developer Tab activated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another quick tip! Removing blank items in a compose</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/removing-blanks-powerautomate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/removing-blanks-powerautomate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a follow-up post for my earlier blog, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/combinemultipledata/&#34;&gt;Combine data from multiple apply to each into a single output file (Variables and compose)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yerawizardcat.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cat Schneider&lt;/a&gt; helped me tremendously on this one, full credit to her! Find her blog here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;pusheenthankyou.gif&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;800&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;1000&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following these steps, results in some empty values also being added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if there is an empty entry, but the item exists and you specify that item it will show up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip! Unmanaged layers - updates not moving through environments (ALM)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/unmanagedlayers-alm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/unmanagedlayers-alm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had this issue today and figured I’d write a quick tip for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve changed my app, modified flows, everything works fine in Dev, publish customizations, export as managed and move to Test. Verified the client can see the new app version, and asked her to test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uh-oh, the flows aren’t reflecting changes.
&lt;img src=&#34;giphy.gif&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;800&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;1000&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;issue-changes-made-in-one-environment-dont-reflect-in-another-environment-in-a-managed-solution&#34;&gt;Issue: Changes made in one environment, don’t reflect in another environment in a managed solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solutionfix-check-on-your-flows-or-anything-not-reflecting-the-changes-for-the-solution-layers&#34;&gt;Solution/Fix: Check on your Flows, or anything not reflecting the changes, for the Solution Layers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to your flow for example, the ellipsis (…) and check the Solution Layers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check if there is an Unmanaged layer there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove this layer, and reimport your package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test and it should have updated, if not, check for more unmanaged layers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-unmanaged-layers-and-why-do-they-occur&#34;&gt;What are unmanaged layers and why do they occur?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a managed solution, and make any edit (could also be just open a flow run and save it) it can create an edited ‘unmanaged’ layer, and this could cause your updates to not go through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get submitted values from your Choices/optionset column in Dataverse</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/collectvalues-choiceoptionsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/collectvalues-choiceoptionsets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ever-noticed-that-when-you-select-your-columnname-in-the-dynamic-data-it-doesnt-give-you-the-result-and-it-stays-blank&#34;&gt;Ever noticed that when you select your columnname, in the dynamic data, it doesnt give you the result and it stays blank?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to explain how you can get the value for your dropdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a difference between the display name, and the actual name of that value.
Dataverse often uses &lt;code&gt;@OData.Community.Display.V1.FormattedValue&lt;/code&gt; instead of the previous &lt;code&gt;new_value_label&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your Power automate flow, either run the flow and check the body, or add a Compose step after your Get Items/Update Item etc. step for Dataverse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do Microsoft exams?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/microsoftexamsvideo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/microsoftexamsvideo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out this video that I did for testpreptraining.com, on how to become a Power Platform Analyst, some tips and how to prepare for a Microsoft exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why become Microsoft Power Platform Developer - Learn with Nathalie Leenders - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vc637VyEsig&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vc637VyEsig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;microsoftexam.png&#34;
    
    
        width=&#34;500&#34;
    
    
        height=&#34;1000&#34;
    
    
    
&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip! Boolean in SQL</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/boolean-in-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/boolean-in-sql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;are-you-looking-for-a-boolean-column-in-sql-or-have-a-virtual-table-and-need-a-togglecheckbox-in-your-app&#34;&gt;Are you looking for a boolean column in SQL? Or have a virtual table and need a toggle/checkbox in your app?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have just a string/text field with True/False this wont work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to convert the column in SQL to BIT.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bit is an integer data type that can take a value of 0, 1, or NULL
1 for true, 0 for false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then reload/refresh your table into your dataverse/virtual table and it can be selected with a checkbox!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataverse Choices to SQL backend- Update!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/dataversechoices-sqlbackend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/dataversechoices-sqlbackend/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the button for “Fork” into “Bork!” for Github</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/forktobork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/forktobork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has to be the best thing to come out of 2023 (and yes, it’s only January so that’s saying something)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My longest blog post and read to date, but I promise you it’s worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on the First Time Contributor training yesterday, one of the Sharing is Caring sessions led by David Warner and Hugo Bernier. (&amp;lt;3) M365 &amp;amp; Power Platform | Sharing Is Caring (pnp.github.io)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this training they explain how Github works, and how to edit an existing item using the Branches, Forks, Committing changes and how a Pull Request works. (I can highly recommend their sessions if you want to learn, there’s no recordings and it’s a safe space for all to ask questions and interrupt)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a count to your Power Automate Flow (Integer/Increment variable)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/countinvariables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/countinvariables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting with an intro to variables, I want to explain how you can use a very simple counter to your Power Automate flow.
Let’s say you have an Apply to each, like 5 entries, and after this you email your client with the combined data from those 5 entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On top of your flow, add an Initialize Variable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Type Integer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave Initial value blank (or select a starting count)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your Apply to each, add an Increment Variable (Increment means to add/change the count)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increment the variable you’ve created on top with 1 in the value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the variable after your Apply to each step wherever you want, and it will give you the count.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combine data from multiple apply to each into a single output file (Variables and compose)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/combinemultipledata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/combinemultipledata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a tricky one to figure out, took me a few hours and failed attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have log entries, and my flow is triggered to email them all that were submitted the day prior, at 8am.
Getting the data into the email pulls it into an apply to each (which makes sense, but is not what I want)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there is a way around the apply to each, but I’ll not get into that here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get conditional images in your Canvas app</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/conditional-images-canvasapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/conditional-images-canvasapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ever-had-a-scenario-where-someone-wanted-to-have-images-in-their-app-but-also-pull-them-from-a-source-somewhere&#34;&gt;Ever had a scenario, where someone wanted to have images in their app, but also pull them from a source somewhere?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say, you want to reflect their office image in your app. But you also want to possibility to overwrite/upload your own instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do this by using an If statement and some variables, let’s look at the following scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You work for a company called Powerplatform with their email domain @Powerplatform.com&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get output from Adaptive Card choice sets</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/adaptivecards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/adaptivecards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adaptive cards is the name for the pop-up you can get in Teams, with custom content asking you to confirm something, or to submit a remark.
One way of creating them is through Adaptive card Designer (JSON).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way is to use the new Cards (preview) method in PowerApps maker - find out how here: Microsoft Learn Page - &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/power-apps/cards/overview/?wt.mc_id=DX-MVP-5005318&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/power-apps/cards/overview/?wt.mc_id=DX-MVP-5005318&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to use your adaptive card as for example an approval, or you want the color choice you need to get the data that the card receives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/posts/alias/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/glossary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;aa--bb--cc--dd--ee--ff--gg--hh--ii--jj--kk--ll--mm--nn--oo--pp--qq--rr--ss--tt--uu--vv--ww--xx--yy--zz-&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a&#34;&gt;A&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#b&#34;&gt;B&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#c&#34;&gt;C&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#d&#34;&gt;D&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#e&#34;&gt;E&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#f&#34;&gt;F&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#g&#34;&gt;G&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#h&#34;&gt;H&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#i&#34;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#j&#34;&gt;J&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#k&#34;&gt;K&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#l&#34;&gt;L&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#m&#34;&gt;M&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#n&#34;&gt;N&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#o&#34;&gt;O&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#p&#34;&gt;P&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#q&#34;&gt;Q&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#s&#34;&gt;S&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#t&#34;&gt;T&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#u&#34;&gt;U&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#v&#34;&gt;V&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#w&#34;&gt;W&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#x&#34;&gt;X&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#y&#34;&gt;Y&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;#z&#34;&gt;Z&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a&#34;&gt;A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Builder&lt;/strong&gt;
Use AI models to enhance your Power Automate Flow or PowerApps, for example extract values (Character recognition) from a pdf upon receiving the file in an email.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/ai-builder/overview/?wt.mc_id=DX-MVP-5005318&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the MS Learn article on AI Builder here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alm (Application Lifecycle Management)&lt;/strong&gt;
The ability to move from Dev, Test and Prod (or other defined) environments maintaining edits in a safe manner without (hopefully) breaking production. Official ALM documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My speaking engagements</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/speakingengagements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/speakingengagements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024 due to personal reasons I havent done many events, but looking forward to doing more in 2025! I have a few event submissions pending, but if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for someone to talk about topics such as Virtual Tables, Imposter Syndrome, Teams Adaptive Cards or many other topics (like Muppets) I&amp;rsquo;d be more than happy to get in touch with you! Love to travel as well for events. Feel free to check out my sessionize profile for my existing sessions, or get in touch for something tailor made.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathalieleenders.com/videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-girl-in-love-with-tech---rachel-irabor-and-nathalie-leendershttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvrx_uxig_sfm&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rx_UXiG_SfM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A girl in love with Tech - Rachel Irabor and Nathalie Leenders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rx_UXiG_SfM?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mvpbuzzchat-with-nathalie-leendershttpswwwyoutubecomwatchva5zw8btcpjq&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a5ZW8BtcPJQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#MVPbuzzChat with Nathalie Leenders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a5ZW8BtcPJQ?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;integrate-power-bi-with-the-power-platform---usergroup-sessionhttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvtbhqd081gtu&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TBHqd081GTU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Integrate Power BI with the Power Platform - Usergroup session&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TBHqd081GTU?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;come-cloud-with-platform---15-hour-panel-womenintech-on-the-power-platform-community-and-morehttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvz1lwi9-4pqm&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z1Lwi9-4pQM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Come Cloud with Platform - 1,5 hour panel #womenintech on the Power Platform, Community and more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z1Lwi9-4pQM?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsoft-new-speakers-community-day---5-min-video-on-an-introverts-tip-to-handling-imposter-syndromehttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvrft7_jv-jt8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFt7_jV-JT8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft New Speakers Community Day - 5 min video on An Introverts Tip to Handling Imposter Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RFt7_jV-JT8?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsoft-new-speakers-community-day---from-zero-to-speakerblogger-in-5-minhttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvx8zewbldapo&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X8zewbldaPo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft New Speakers Community Day - From zero to speaker/blogger in 5 min&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X8zewbldaPo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;smart-cherry-thoughtshttpswwwyoutubecomembedvdjfajcdzyw&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VdJFAJcDZYw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Smart Cherry Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VdJFAJcDZYw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsoft-power-platform-connects---nathalie-leendershttpswwwyoutubecomembedl4c3zfpo8dy&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L4c3ZFpo8dY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft Power Platform Connects - Nathalie Leenders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L4c3ZFpo8dY?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-prep-trainingcom-why-become-a-microsoft-power-platform-developerhttpswwwyoutubecomembedvc637vyesig&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vc637VyEsig&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Test Prep Training.com Why become a Microsoft Power Platform Developer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vc637VyEsig?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-tech-townhall-tallinn-overviewaftermovie-i-was-featured-inhttpswwwyoutubecomembedi6wcbqnytbe&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i6WcBqNYTbE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cloud Tech Townhall Tallinn Overview/Aftermovie I was featured in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i6WcBqNYTbE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-demo-on-the-power-platform-community-callhttpswwwyoutubecomembedcr9oqwqzk2a&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cr9oqwQzk2A&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;My demo on the Power Platform Community call&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cr9oqwQzk2A?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
